<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-09T18:39:52+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tech Right Now</title><subtitle>The Tech Right Now blog - anything and everything relating to tech and more.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">What the hell are NFTs?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crypto/2021/03/07/what-the-hell-are-nfts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What the hell are NFTs?" /><published>2021-03-07T17:00:21+11:00</published><updated>2021-03-07T17:00:21+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crypto/2021/03/07/what-the-hell-are-nfts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crypto/2021/03/07/what-the-hell-are-nfts.html">&lt;p&gt;By now you’ve probably heard about this cool new thing called NFTs that are absolutely blowing up. Seemingly absurd amounts of money are being paid for all forms of digital art: JPEGs, GIFs, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; NFTs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NFT stands for ‘&lt;strong&gt;non-fungible token&lt;/strong&gt;’ — something being fungible means that it can be exchanged for the exact same thing, and so NFTs aren’t exchangeable/interchangeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s think of an example here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had a trading card (ie: Pokemon) that I wanted to trade off, I could give you that trading card in exchange for another trading card, and at the end of the deal I’ll be left with the same item; a trading card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, NFTs are one of a kind. This means that I can’t give you an NFT and get the exact same thing back, as the NFT that I have given you is the only one in existence. So if I had an ultra-rare, limited edition trading card of which there was only one ever made, then I could trade it with you for anything &lt;strong&gt;other than&lt;/strong&gt; the trading card&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is because the limited edition card is the only one of itself in existence, therefore making it non-fungible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NFTs operate on the Ethereum blockchain and are built on one of two token standards: ERC-721 and ERC-1155 — you don’t need to know this as the average consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*VWuVKj5ZIH2WKclcUAZntQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonnie in the Sea #1 by Chris David&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ok-so-if-you-were-to-download-the-picture-above-would-you-suddenly-have-the-nft-have-you-cheated-thesystem&quot;&gt;Ok, so if you were to download the picture above, would you suddenly have the NFT? Have you cheated the system?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well…not quite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, the value in having these NFTs (for those who buy them) is having the &lt;strong&gt;original copy of the work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the difference between having a picture of the Mona Lisa on my phone versus actually having the original Mona Lisa canvas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst you may be able to look at the image above and download it for your viewing pleasure, you would never actually own the work. This means that you can’t gain any value from it, as the NFT is tokenized and recorded as being the original copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, it works in the favour of a collector to have other people view the artwork that they own — the more that people view the artwork, the more they share it, the more valuable the original becomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It certainly raises an interesting point about whether authenticity is what makes the artwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-do-nfts-mean-for-creators&quot;&gt;What do NFTs mean for creators?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually pretty good for creators to be selling NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creators keep anywhere from 85–97(ish) percent of the primary sale (depending on which platform the creator chooses), and if the NFT gets sold again on the secondary market, the artist makes 10% of those secondary sales, which is essentially passive revenue for the artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, artists can still retain the copyright and reproduction rights to the work, so not all control is lost by the artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-about-the-environment&quot;&gt;What about the environment?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the bitter part about NFTs. Since it runs on the same technology as cryptocurrency, the impacts that NFTs have on the environment are similar — negative impacts that continue to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, the total yearly carbon footprint of Bitcoin energy consumption is comparable to &lt;a href=&quot;https://digiconomist.net/bitcoin-energy-consumption&quot;&gt;New Zealand’s footprint&lt;/a&gt; — and that’s just Bitcoin, not including Ethereum and all the other coins there are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there’s definitely a negative impact on the environment from buying and selling NFTs — &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/u/4f2c96a401a3&quot;&gt;everest pipkin&lt;/a&gt; published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://everestpipkin.medium.com/but-the-environmental-issues-with-cryptoart-1128ef72e6a3&quot;&gt;great piece&lt;/a&gt; about this the other day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-can-you-buynfts&quot;&gt;Where can you buy NFTs?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can buy NFTs in a number of marketplaces such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensea.io&quot;&gt;OpenSea&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://foundation.app&quot;&gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rarible.com&quot;&gt;Rarible&lt;/a&gt; and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;find-more-like-this-at-tech-rightnow&quot;&gt;Find more like this at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/tech-right-now&quot;&gt;Tech Right Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="crypto" /><summary type="html">A new type of digital art that’s blowing up</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TikTok — Powerful for Marketing?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2020/07/09/tiktok-powerful-for-marketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TikTok — Powerful for Marketing?" /><published>2020-07-09T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-09T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2020/07/09/tiktok-powerful-for-marketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/socialmedia/2020/07/09/tiktok-powerful-for-marketing.html">&lt;p&gt;TikTok- the platform once popularly known as Musical.ly, rebranded to TikTok in August of 2018, has been taking over the app stores, with the app itself having over 800 million active users. Its demographic is primarily 16–24-year-olds, and with a million videos viewed per day, its clear to see why both content creators and brands would want to be on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On TikTok, a user can choose between 15, 30 or 60-second videos, in which they can either record their own sound or have a sound overlaid from the app (which has a huge selection of songs and random ‘memes’). And this extremely short-form content can grab millions and millions of young eyes, making it a great platform to market both oneself and one’s brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’m going to be looking at how TikTok can be useful for both the individual, and the brand level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-individual&quot;&gt;The Individual&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*6SjNUIZVGHtXFYCjf9TYmA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The D’Amelio’s (Photo courtesy of Christopher Lane/The Guardian)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charli D’Amelio. A name that, just a year ago was not heard of at all, but now at just 16, she’s one of the biggest influencers on TikTok, having racked up a massive &lt;strong&gt;67.7 million followers&lt;/strong&gt; at the time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the best example of how someone can easily skyrocket to fame on TikTok. Last year, the D’Amelio’s were an ordinary family, just like any other, and now, they have a collective TikTok following of 117M followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a matter of months, their lives transformed forever, and their influence has gotten to such a substantial level to the point where (according to The Rolling Stone) Charli can charge anywhere from $25-$40k USD per sponsored post. And it’s clear to see why brands would be willing to spend so much money just to get 30 seconds on her platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiktok has greatly reduced the friction when it comes to liking or sharing a post, and this is why it has that great viral potential. In addition to this, like with any other platform, trends ebb and flow through the app, with various hashtags and sounds that relate to the trend being present, meaning that if one uses those hashtags, and uses the sound for that particular trend, they too could end up on the “For You Page”, and there, if their post gets traction, they are given exposure to users who like their content. And this cycle continues. People can quickly build followings of &amp;gt;100k followers, and if you operate within a niche (ie: tech/health/etc) you can find your audience and continue to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We make it easy for you to discover and create your own original videos by providing easy-to-use tools to view and capture your daily moments. Take your videos to the next level with special effects, filters, music, and more. — TikTok&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m trying to say is that, at an individual level, TikTok is a fantastic platform with great leverage for personal brand growth, and its no wonder that each day, more and more creators who are established on other platforms jump on to TikTok — there’s a whole new audience to get the attention of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-brand&quot;&gt;The Brand&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the individuals who use TikTok, countless brands have established a presence on TikTok. In particular, I’m going to be looking at the account from The Washington Post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something cool about TikTok with brands is that the style of the content, as well as the length of it, allows for brands to take a little bit more of a relaxed and fun approach with the content it uploads, which in my opinion helps the brand connect with the users on a more personal level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take The Washington Post. They are known for (naturally) their news, with a serious approach to delivering the new stories of the day to those around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*ikTuvBN308Lc_JDNurcffw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*aIOl-dZX1-lC2korIPfMWw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Washington Post on TikTok (left) and Twitter (right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, there’s a wildly different style of content between the two, with the Twitter content being strictly news, whereas the TikTok content is much more relaxed, with funny memes, staff jokes, and TikTok trends, which are most of the time not related to the news and current issues of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, hundreds of thousands of people still follow the TikTok page — why? It’s because of how &lt;strong&gt;relatable&lt;/strong&gt; the Washington Post’s content is. And that right there is why TikTok is a quick and easy platform to build customer relations on. It doesn’t have to be formal and can be more relatable to the consumers compared to a platform like Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subsequently, &lt;strong&gt;trends are something that brands can use to their advantage&lt;/strong&gt;. If they can get a trend and a hashtag ‘challenge’ going, the brand is able to reach wide audiences across TikTok. A good example of this would be the &lt;em&gt;#inmydenim&lt;/em&gt; challenge that was created by Guess. This challenge simply involved the users showing the various ways in which they wear their Guess jeans. Guess collaborated with influencers to get the trend going, and soon they reached upwards of &lt;strong&gt;40 million views across the platform&lt;/strong&gt;, which is incredible reach for an ad campaign, and these videos continue to receive engagement on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, there you have it — TikTok is a fantastic platform for both an individual’s brand or a larger, corporate brand to reach eyes across the world. As to whether TikTok will last the test of time, that is yet to be seen — but for now, TikTok is a platform that everyone who wants to be heard should go on.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use TikTok &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/ug/app/tiktok-make-your-day/id835599320&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for iOS, &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zhiliaoapp.musically&amp;amp;hl=en_AU&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for Android and &lt;a href=&quot;http://tiktok.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for desktop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="socialmedia" /><summary type="html">Here’s why TikTok is a must-use for anyone wanting to spread their brand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ratio, A New Minimalist Launcher</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/smartphones/2020/07/07/a-new-minimalist-launcher.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ratio, A New Minimalist Launcher" /><published>2020-07-07T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-07T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/smartphones/2020/07/07/a-new-minimalist-launcher</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/smartphones/2020/07/07/a-new-minimalist-launcher.html">&lt;p&gt;Blloc — it’s a company that you probably haven’t heard of before. They’re a Berlin based startup, who made a phone called the Blloc Zero 18, a phone that they marketed as the “minimalist smartphone”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty average midrange phone, with a design that was reminiscent of the iPhone X (which is something that a lot of budget Androids tend to do). It’s major standout features however, were what they called ‘Blloc Mode’. It’s a mode where, when enabled, the regular homescreen transforms into one made of tiles, with your most used apps being tiles and notifications. It’s a completely rethought Android experience, and a cool one at that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Blloc, the phone ended up selling out, but now it seems that they are taking a turn to focus on bringing the software features of the Blloc Z18 onto other devices via an Android launcher, as many have requested it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introducing Blloc Ratio, a launcher that is designed to help you use your phone more intentionally so that you don’t find yourself having spent hours on a distracting app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;home-page&quot;&gt;Home Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s made up of two pages — the Root and the Drawers. The Root is a page where you can add little widgets such as the weather, RSS feeds, conversion tools, Spotify playback and more. The Root is primarily a page that’s designed to have information at a glance so that you can use apps less and get the info you need quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*WQtDlgFxrsocG_rKZZu5pg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Root (left) and the Drawer (right)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Drawers on the other hand, are essentially an app drawer, but not in the traditional sense. The apps are automatically sorted into labels such as ‘Essential’, ‘Favourites’, ‘Most Used’ and ‘Other’, and as far as I can tell, these categories are made using your usage data (which is something that you give them permissions for when installing Blloc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apps within the drawers can be easily rearranged, and the button at the bottom right corner (when held) brings up three options : Focus Mode, Sun Mode, and the option for a new drawer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*YuhlhjVwoAgtwS9u3s-ATQ.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Focus Mode at the time of writing does not do much apart from putting a border around all the apps and increasing their visibility, but more features are being added month after month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sun Mode is a button that inverts the colours of the launcher, making it white overall, and thus increasing visibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the home interface is nice, clean, and minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;customisation&quot;&gt;Customisation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This launcher provides a customisation experience that I haven’t quite seen this well implemented in other launchers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of this are the various options that it provides you with to customise on an app-by-app basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*bP2W5n5kWJ1pWd86Y3Jb2g.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As seen in the screenshot on the left, when you hold and release an app in the Drawers, it brings up this app dashboard of sorts, showing you a wide variety of data such as how much &lt;strong&gt;storage and mobile data the app has used&lt;/strong&gt;, your &lt;strong&gt;usage time,&lt;/strong&gt; as well as extra options such as force stopping/deleting the app, changing the icon of it and the rotation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then at the bottom of this dashboard are where I think the coolest features are: you can &lt;strong&gt;enable greyscale&lt;/strong&gt; on an app by app basis, you can &lt;strong&gt;hide it from the app drawer&lt;/strong&gt; so that its harder to get to, you can &lt;strong&gt;lock the app with biometrics&lt;/strong&gt; and you can mute the sound in the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that this launcher provides you with the ability to have it on an app by app case is something that I found very useful, as it meant that I could have certain apps such as the camera app set to always have colour, whereas I could have apps that distract me (Instagram, Reddit) to be greyscale so that I got discouraged from scrolling through them. I found it to be quite effective and well implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biometric locking of each app was something that I also found to be implemented well compared to other Android launchers. It worked smoothly and always locked whenever my device went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-effective-wasit&quot;&gt;How Effective Was It?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be completely honest, going into this launcher, I was not expecting it to have a significant impact on my phone usage, but after enabling the app-by-app greyscale, I found it to be working quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was using Instagram and Reddit much less than before, mostly due to the monochrome effect which a) made the content of the app less appealing to look at but also b) triggered me to think about why I was using my phone, and subsequently, be more intentional with my phone use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did notice was a slightly increased battery drain, but that might be different for others, as I’m on a Google Pixel 2 XL that’s rooted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another small thing that I hope Blloc adds down the road is Quickswitch support — it’s a small thing (most people won’t even notice it) but it would go a long way in making the experience smoother for users who are on stock Android 10 or are rooted like myself. &lt;em&gt;[Quickswitch is a Magisk (root) Module that enables for smooth integration between the recents page and a custom launcher.]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;verdict&quot;&gt;Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*WuAFhQruvvbdHOU_5pxUaw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Courtesy of Tech Altar on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I thought that Blloc Ratio was a great Android launcher, and it certainly delivered on what it aimed to do. It really made me think about my phone usage, and in general this has been something highly beneficial for me, as it has made me be more intentional with the time I spend on my phone, thus making each minute on my phone one that brings me value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ratio had a well implemented monochrome system and theme that worked the way they intended it to, and I highly appreciated the fact that they gave quite a decent amount of control over this feature to the user, something that allows for a custom fit for each person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, as it is still an early release, it does have some issues with stability and smoothness such as the recents issue I mentioned above (which also sometimes causes the launcher to freeze up, something that can only be remedied by going to the homescreen) as well as the issue with the battery usage. &lt;strong&gt;It is still in early release though, which is something to be kept in mind.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can only wait and see from now to see what other updates Blloc brings to the table with their Ratio launcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-try-itout&quot;&gt;Want To Try It Out?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sign up for a Blloc invitation code &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blloc.com/#ratio&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="smartphones" /><summary type="html">Take A Look At This Company’s Approach To Reducing Your Phone Usage</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Digital Tools to Help You Be More Productive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/productivity/2020/07/02/5-digital-tools-productivity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Digital Tools to Help You Be More Productive" /><published>2020-07-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/productivity/2020/07/02/5-digital-tools-productivity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/productivity/2020/07/02/5-digital-tools-productivity.html">&lt;p&gt;Behind every productive person is a system — one that is able to carry thoughts and ideas, and one that is able to be a person’s ‘second brain’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I am not saying that these apps will suddenly multiply your productivity, but they certainly can help you get more things done. For more on productivity, I’d recommend checking out&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skillshare.com/classes/Productivity-Masterclass-Create-a-Custom-System-that-Works/442860604&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thomas Frank’s Skillshare clas&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;s (not sponsored by the way).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-todoist&quot;&gt;1. Todoist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most productive people use a to-do list, whether it be in a notebook or on an app. Here is my personal favourite — Todoist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great to-do list app with a plethora of features, with one of my favourite being the &lt;strong&gt;Natural Language Processing.&lt;/strong&gt; What this does is basically recognise certain key words that you use when putting in a task, and it can adjust the parameters of the task to automatically fit your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, if I wrote “Write Medium post at 7AM on the 2nd of July”, Todoist would highlight the ‘7AM on the 2nd of July’ part and automatically set the task to remind me at 7AM on the 2nd of July. The importance of this feature (in my opinion) is that it greatly decreases the friction between having a thought and entering it into one’s system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features include being able to have a streak, being able to set a daily minimum task completion, and organisation is super easy in Todoist. You can have tasks within tasks, divide them into projects, and then divide those projects into sections. Overall I really like Todoist, and although I am aware other apps exist, Todoist hasn’t disappointed yet, and it’s great for anyone looking to have an organised to-do list on all devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Todoist &lt;a href=&quot;https://todoist.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-notion&quot;&gt;2. Notion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fantastic note-taking app that is super customisable and easy to use. It’s got a strong community over at r/Notion, and they have a lot of user built templated available for use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s got cross-platform support, and the team over at Notion are making strides to introduce a Notion API (integration ftw). I personally find that Notion is helpful for tracking habits, as well as taking notes in general for school and other tasks. I will admit, whilst its mobile apps aren’t the best, the web and desktop versions generally run quite well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*IsY78PM1hprem_bJgMYXLA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Notion template by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@benln&quot;&gt;Ben Lang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried using OneNote and other such note-taking platforms, but I find myself coming back to Notion due to the great interface (more on that &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/tech-right-now/notion-and-the-value-of-delight-26618b5f725c&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), as well as the great customisation in my notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re looking for a great note-taking app (with a myriad of features) look no further than Notion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Notion &lt;a href=&quot;http://notion.so&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-googlecalendar&quot;&gt;3. Google Calendar&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t already heard of it, well, here is what I think is the best free, cross-platform calendar app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to get started is a Google account, and thats it. You get access to a Calendar with a great UI, and great integration with the G Suite (especially if you use an Android device). It’s super simply to enter events in, and you have options to add people, schedule a meeting on Google Meet, location, a description of the event, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*lTg-2QvlwZe5c7Od47Fnnw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the options you get when scheduling an event into Google Calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, as most calendar apps have, you have the option of adding in external calendars, either through a link, email address, and you can share a calendar to other people via a link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: I am aware of other calendar aps such as Fantastical, which have NLP and other cool features, but I think that the cross platform functionality of Google Calendar is hard to beat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, for a free app, Google Calendar is a fantastic service which you can use to organise your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Google Calendar &lt;a href=&quot;http://calendar.google.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-microsoft-officelens&quot;&gt;4. Microsoft Office Lens&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the world getting closer and closer to a paperless world, I’m sure that there are many of us who have papers and documents lying around that we would like to digitize, or perhaps we need to scan something to send to a friend. Whatever the case may be, in my experience, Office Lens is a great app to help achieve this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*XhY0NdEg-YX79eFQS4bIbQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save options in Microsoft Lens&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s great for scanning documents, with many options to scan such as ‘document’, ‘whiteboard’, ‘business card’ and ‘photo’. It has resizing options (although it normally gets it first try) and captures nice and clear scans. It can also automatically upload scans to your OneDrive account, which, if you’re like me, is a godsend, as it means that I can scan something on my phone and get it on my laptop only a few minutes later. It can also upload it into OneNote, save it in your device’s gallery, put it into a Word Doc, and put it in a PowerPoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, it’s a pretty great scanning app and in my opinion, a must have to organise various documents and digital files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Office Lens &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/au/app/microsoft-office-lens-pdf-scan/id975925059&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (for iOS) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.office.officelens&amp;amp;hl=en_AU&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (for Android).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-otter-voicenotes&quot;&gt;5. Otter Voice Notes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever been in a lecture, you know that sometimes, the lecturer just goes way too fast, and you can miss out on important notes. Well, with just your smartphone, transcription has never been easier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otter Voice Notes is a great app for voice to text transcription, and its packed with features such as live transcription, automatic distinction between speakers, and a whole heap of sharing features. It’s also got an inbuilt search where you can search based on the specific word you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it isn’t always perfect in the transcription, but that’s why the audio file’s there as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more on Otter, and a demonstration, check out my video &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/zDzHwhvLntc?t=71&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (the video is skipped to 71 seconds.) Feel free to subscribe while you’re at it:)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use Otter Voice Notes &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/au/app/otter-voice-meeting-notes/id1276437113&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (for iOS) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aisense.otter&amp;amp;hl=en_AU&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (for Android).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;so-there-they-are--my-personal-top-5-productivity-apps-i-hope-you-get-the-same-value-from-them-as-ihave&quot;&gt;So there they are- my personal top 5 productivity apps. I hope you get the same value from them as I have.&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">Here are my favourite tools that help me get my work done.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">OnePlus returning to their roots with the OnePlus Nord</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/02/oneplus-return-roots.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OnePlus returning to their roots with the OnePlus Nord" /><published>2020-07-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/02/oneplus-return-roots</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/02/oneplus-return-roots.html">&lt;p&gt;Ahh, OnePlus. The self proclaimed “flagship-killer”. The brand that undercut the competition so severely that it attracted a large amount of hype, got a massive amount of traction and here they are today, 15 phones later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*Bdv1Fh2TmgTOtZV74pcRzA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But over the years, the prices of OnePlus phones have been going up and up — as they say, “you either die a hero, or live long enough to see yourself become the villain”, and OnePlus phones which were once flagship killers, are now flagships in the full sense of the word, with their latest OnePlus 8 starting at $799USD and the 8 Pro starting at a whopping $999USD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that brings us to about two weeks ago, when the @OneplusLiteZThing Instagram page was started. They started dropping the occasional teaser, with various Polaroid photos of staff working, and design ‘leaks’. Then, they came out with an official name — Nord, and with it a new Instagram account (@OnePlus.Nord).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*ZMLxipKo-g0WmbZ17UR_xg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The OnePlus Nord Instagram Page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the Instagram page building the hype, they’ve also made a four part documentary series, ‘New Beginning’, to document the journey of creating this phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To quote their page “It’s been a while since we’ve done anything like this.”, and they’ve talked about how the OnePlus Nord is going to be a sub $500 phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve got OnePlus back at it again, churning the hype up for their next phone drop. One can only wait and see what comes out of this ambitious project. Will the OnePlus Nord come out with OnePlus One levels of hype, or will it flop?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally think that if they can undercut the competition like they used to while including decent specs and performance for the phone, they can absolutely dominate the competition in the $500 price range. I look forward to seeing more updates from the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/u/467a949d63d4&quot;&gt;OnePlus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go check out our Twitter page&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TechRightNow1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;for quicker, bite size tech insights and updates on the OnePlus Nord.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do we have such an aversion to buying paid apps?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/consumertech/2020/07/01/aversion-to-paid-apps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do we have such an aversion to buying paid apps?" /><published>2020-07-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-07-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/consumertech/2020/07/01/aversion-to-paid-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/consumertech/2020/07/01/aversion-to-paid-apps.html">&lt;p&gt;As someone who is interested in technology, I’ve noticed that in videos that demo an app or service, often times the first couple of comments are “is it free?” or “how about a free version?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*MDBk9ngW5yXhhz4OZWfQAA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to think that many of us would have no issue with spending 3–4$ on a coffee but refuse to spend that money on a one-off app purchase (which can sometimes bring heaps of value).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, let’s take the app/website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.notion.so&quot;&gt;Notion&lt;/a&gt; (which I’ve talked about &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/tech-right-now/notion-and-the-value-of-delight-26618b5f725c&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; by the way) is a productivity app that myself and many others have found extremely useful and something that vastly increases productive input and output as a whole. Yet, there are many people who are averse to paying the $4 a month that it costs for the Personal Pro plan (which is the plan I would personally recommend for most people). The $4 a month that Notion costs is much, much less than the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ngpf.org/blog/budgeting/question-of-the-day-how-much-do-millennials-spend-every-year-on-coffee/&quot;&gt;$92 a month&lt;/a&gt; that most American millenials spend on coffee. So, what is this dislike to spending for online goods and services?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, most people don’t realise that the purchase cost of an app might be free, but often times you are paying something else in return for using the app — whether it be through ad exposure, the app collecting analytics on you and selling it and many more. That’s not to say that a paid app won’t collect data as well, but very often paid apps don’t have ads and are less intrusive on that front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently read an interesting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.quora.com/Psychology/Why-are-people-willing-to-pay-4-for-a-bag-of-chips-but-not-1-for-an-app/answer/%E0%AE%AA%E0%AE%BE%E0%AE%B2%E0%AE%BE%E0%AE%9C%E0%AE%BF-%E0%AE%B5%E0%AE%BF%E0%AE%B8%E0%AF%8D%E0%AE%B5%E0%AE%A8%E0%AE%BE%E0%AE%A4%E0%AE%A9%E0%AF%8D-Balaji-Viswanathan&quot;&gt;Quora answer&lt;/a&gt; on why people tend to spend less on apps, with the summary essentially being that anchor prices were set since the beginnings of these app stores (ie 0.99c or free) and these anchor prices influence the way that we think an app should be reasonably priced. Do check the full answer out, it’s a short, interesting read on anchor prices. The point that I’m trying to make is this- we have preconceived notions of a value that an app can bring to our lives, and we mentally set a price limit on what we would be willing to shell out to increase that value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly there seems to be a generational aspect that comes into this question of why we are so hesitant to spend money online. Most of you reading probably grew up when the internet was in its early years, and back then the internet was a much more ‘dodgy’ place to buy from compared to now, with highly established marketplaces and sellers. This attitude might have carried over from our parents to us, which is why we are so reluctant to spend money on apps. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/311447943_Why_Consumers_Hesitate_to_Shop_Online_Perceived_Risk_and_Product_Involvement_on_Taobaocom&quot;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; done by researchers Min Chung Han and Youjeong Kim showed that in China (1), “product risk and social/psychological risk were negatively associated with consumer’s trust and purchase intention [in relation to Chinese e-commerce platform Taobao]”. Granted, this study was conducted amongst Chinese students, and was specific for Taobao, but it’s clear that this is the sort of attitude held by us when it comes to apps — we’re worried that the apps aren’t going to be as promised, or that they won’t bring enough value to our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to propose an idea to you- the reader- next time you’re hesitating over the purchase of an app, or an online service, think to yourself about the amount of value that this app could potentially bring to your life, and how in context with all other expenditure, a mere $5–10 is nothing for a service that could potentially help us with work or life. I know that for me certainly, spending money on apps is something that is hard to swallow, but after discovering Notion, and other paid apps which have greatly helped me, I am starting to realise that maybe I don’t have to Google “[insert app name here] crack version”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(1) Han, Min Chung &amp;amp; Kim, Youjeong. (2017). Why Consumers Hesitate to Shop Online: Perceived Risk and Product Involvement on Taobao.com. Journal of Promotion Management. 23. 1–21. 10.1080/10496491.2016.1251530.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="consumertech" /><summary type="html">As someone who is interested in technology, I’ve noticed that in videos that demo an app or service, often times the first couple of comments are “is it free?” or “how about a free version?”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The iPad Pro — a viable laptop replacement?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/consumertech/2020/06/30/ipad-pro-viable.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The iPad Pro — a viable laptop replacement?" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/consumertech/2020/06/30/ipad-pro-viable</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/consumertech/2020/06/30/ipad-pro-viable.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Is there room for a third category of device in the middle? Something that’s between a laptop and a smartphone.” — Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2010, Steve Jobs announced a device that would impact the computing and portable technology space forever- the iPad. Introduced as an offering in between the iPhone and the Macbook, and it was the first tablet that really took off, selling 300,000 units on its first day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*dOFNTMUWjymO0OjgOEgdDg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2020, and Apple is still dominating in the tablet game. We’ve also seen Samsung and various other Android based OEM’s introduce their tablets, but none have been as popular in both the education and consumer sectors as the iPads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple released the first generation of the iPad Pro in 2015, and since then on, coming up to the fourth generation of iPad Pros, they have been advertising them as laptop replacements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the latest iPad Pro- it comes really, really close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when talking about a laptop replacement, it raises the question, what really is a laptop? What is so inherently different from an iPad that we would rather use a laptop? For everyone, the answer is drastically different. For a video editor, the reason might be because Premiere Pro/Final Cut Pro is only available on desktop platforms. For a graphic designer, that reason may be that Illustrator is on desktop platforms only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for the common user, one that types up documents, does some research, watches YouTube videos, maybe plays a couple of games and does some light sketching on Procreate? The iPad Pro is perfect for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even then, there are more solutions coming for creative professionals to at least use the iPad Pro as a devices for light work. Software like LumaFusion means that higher grade video-editing is actually possible on something like the iPad Pro, especially with the power of the current A12Z Bionic Chip. Adobe Photoshop, Procreate, and all these other softwares that are coming to the iPad means that creative professional work is slowly becoming more of a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPad now has native mouse support, and with its new Magic Keyboard, its easier than ever to get used to the navigation around iPadOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/900/1*CiDJkbACheJtM0B49qBp6w.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple’s new Magic Keyboard Case. Image Courtesy of Apple&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Magic Keyboard Case. Image Courtesy of Apple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it comes to looking at whether or not the iPad Pro is a viable purchase, things like build quality, performance, etc are things that I won’t look at here, simply because they have been covered in depth by other YouTubers and websites, and even then it is an incremental update — the build is virtually the same as last year (it’s a really great build quality), the performance is even more improved than before, and the screen is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question really comes down to whether you can make a transition over from Windows/MacOS over to the iPad, and whether the returns you get from moving to a smaller device is worth the $1000 that the iPad costs (without Apple Pencil).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion: is the iPad Pro worth it? 100% yes. With a great build quality, amazing performance and time tested software support from Apple, you cannot go wrong with this device. Before getting it however, you should take a long, hard look at your workflow, and whether you would be better off staying with a PC/Mac.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="consumertech" /><summary type="html">Spoiler: Maybe. It really depends on your situation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Notion and the Value of Delight</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/productivity/2020/04/24/notion-and-value-delight.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notion and the Value of Delight" /><published>2020-04-24T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-24T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/productivity/2020/04/24/notion-and-value-delight</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/productivity/2020/04/24/notion-and-value-delight.html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few months, I’ve been using a notetaking app called Notion, and it’s a pretty great software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s jam-packed with features and I personally found it to be really flexible whether it came to structuring things or putting my thoughts down into Notion, I can always find a way to do it how I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But aside from the great features and cross-platform functionality, a major thing that I noticed when using it was how much of a delight it was to use, and as pretentious as it sounds, the user interface and design are so well done that it “motivates” me in a sense to write more and be more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*gk_YnbRHZi9laZtSbh_m2A.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Notion template by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/u/24bbea13727&quot;&gt;Ben Lang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion has a lot of options for how you want to make pages look and feel, and you can put in icons (as shown above) and more. It’s really flexible, and you can drag and drop “blocks”, which are essentially units of content/text/pictures etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes for a highly customisable experience which can be changed to suit the way you work and the way you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a web app, with native apps on Windows, MacOS, Android and iOS, meaning that you can work on one device and then pick up on the next seamlessly (albeit the fact that an internet connection is needed in order to sync across devices, and the mobile apps still require more work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, you really should try out Notion. If you’re coming from something like OneNote or Evernote, the file structure may seem a little bit chaotic to you, but thats only because you can have it any way you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notion starts off with a free plan with a 1000 blocks, a personal plan for $4 a month (can be free with a .edu or .ac email address) and a team and enterprise plan, for $8 and $20 respectively.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links to popular Notion videos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/66fN1cZadPA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m9S5I3pWz94&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ONG26-2mIHU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="productivity" /><summary type="html">Here’s why Notion’s clean interface is part of the genius behind it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An iPhone is now cheaper than a OnePlus phone — here’s why the Pixel 4a is going to have a hard time</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/smartphones/2020/04/21/iphone-cheap-oneplus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An iPhone is now cheaper than a OnePlus phone — here’s why the Pixel 4a is going to have a hard time" /><published>2020-04-21T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/smartphones/2020/04/21/iphone-cheap-oneplus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/smartphones/2020/04/21/iphone-cheap-oneplus.html">&lt;p&gt;Apple has just recently announced the return of the iPhone SE, starting at USD$399, a model that was first introduced back in 2016, it only saw one generation until a few days ago, when Apple came out with the second — gen iPhone SE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*Tzh5goicosMDyA0N-6iVpg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Source: Apple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And only a few days before that, OnePlus unveiled its brand new OnePlus 8 and 8 Pro, with the latter now costing USD$899 for the starting price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1200/1*ctpWrzliWeGY9CUC3I-YGQ.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OnePlus, which first started off as the “flagship killer” has now become a flagship, whilst Apple has put their latest CPU, their latest image processing algorithm (SmartHDR) and water resistance in a compact package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unexpected entry by Apple into this space of sub $700 smartphones is quite the disruptor, as for the past few years, Android manufacturers like Xiaomi, Oppo, Nokia, Motorola, and even Google with the Pixel 3a have been dominating this space. There was never an iOS option, so if you wanted a new phone in that price range, you would have had to go for one of the Android phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a space where companies could cut certain specs and features in order to reach the price level, Apple coming through with a lot of flagship features for not a huge price severely undercuts the competition. Sure, it may not have the latest bezel-less design or pop-up camera, but at that pricepoint most people are not looking for the latest bleeding edge features, and rather, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;value for money and reliability.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now where does the Pixel 4a come in to the equation? Last year, Google made an impact in the budget smartphone space when they brought their flagship camera technology and processing down into a package that retailed for only $799, with frequent discounts and deals from Google. This year, rumours already show us that the “a” series is going to make a return, with leaked specs showing a Snapdragon 730, a 5.18 inch screen, a 12.2 MP rear camera and no water resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming that it comes at the same price point as last year, it’s going to be competing directly with the iPhone SE, and unfortunately it seems like the Pixel 4a is going to have to offer more than just its trademark Pixel camera, as the iPhone brings down their excellent camera and more. Will it have Motion Sense? We’ll just have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider is that iOS just has much better software support, so if you wanted to pick a phone based on its durability in the long run, the iPhone is the definite choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for now, the iPhone SE has the upper hand, but things can very well change by the time of the release of the Pixel 4a.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="smartphones" /><summary type="html">Apple has just recently announced the return of the iPhone SE, starting at USD$399, a model that was first introduced back in 2016, it only saw one generation until a few days ago, when Apple came out with the second — gen iPhone SE.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How you can use the power of your PC to help the fight against COVID-19</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/covid19/2020/04/07/power-of-pc-for-covid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How you can use the power of your PC to help the fight against COVID-19" /><published>2020-04-07T16:00:21+10:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T16:00:21+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/covid19/2020/04/07/power-of-pc-for-covid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/covid19/2020/04/07/power-of-pc-for-covid.html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;all-about-foldinghome&quot;&gt;All about Folding@Home.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*w2RWj3sbPYTXA4ub&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@christianw?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot;&gt;Christian Wiediger&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com?utm_source=medium&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these times of crisis with the coronavirus, it is imperative for society to band together and help each other to get through this. One way you can help is with &lt;a href=&quot;https://foldingathome.org/&quot;&gt;Folding@Home&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick intro to Folding@Home- it was first introduced in 2018 as a “distributed computing project for simulating protein dynamics”. The way that Folding@Home works is by using your unused computing power from your CPU and GPU in order to run protein simulations and solve problems collectively with thousands of computers around the world. More detailed information about how it works can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://foldingathome.org/support/faq/project-details/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you can do:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a spare computer lying around that you aren’t using, or even the computer that you are using, you can install Folding@Home and get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It works on all 3 major platforms- Windows, Mac and Linux, and there are detailed instructions on the Folding@Home website which is linked above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Work Units” which are parts of protein simulations are given to your computer through the client installed on your computer. Once your computer finishes running the simulation, it will send back the Work Unit and receive another one, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*QwU5SEXHyTDuYXJhXJLdOw.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, there are setting that you can use in order to customise how much of your computing power can be used, and when. There is also a big red button that can stop the folding process if you need all the power of your computer for a task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go ahead, dig out that old laptop, install Folding@Home on it and do your bit to help in the fight against COVID-19 (or other projects that are being &lt;a href=&quot;https://foldingathome.org/start-folding/&quot;&gt;worked on&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to Folding@Home: &lt;a href=&quot;https://foldingathome.org/&quot;&gt;https://foldingathome.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to Folding@Home setup tutorial : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OYOnSLjYLwE&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OYOnSLjYLwE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Senvidu Jayaweera</name></author><category term="covid19" /><summary type="html">All about Folding@Home.</summary></entry></feed>